<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-03T20:09:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Yash Jain</title><subtitle>My personal blog</subtitle><author><name>Yash Jain</name></author><entry><title type="html">HPCC Internship : First Week Over!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/10/hpcc-internship-first-week.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HPCC Internship : First Week Over!!" /><published>2019-05-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-05-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/10/hpcc-internship-first-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/10/hpcc-internship-first-week.html">Hi there.

I just finished the first week of my internship at [HPCC systems](https://hpccsystems.com/). Those who don't know about the company, here's a breif intro from the their [about page](https://hpccsystems.com/about#Platform)
&gt; The HPCC Systems platform is a set of easy-to-use software features, enabling developers and data scientists to process and analyze data at any scale.

I am working on making the deployment easier. I will be using Juju cluster deployment framework to achieve this. I am being mentored by [Xiaoming Wang](https://www.linkedin.com/in/xiaoming-wang-749aaa99) and [Kevin Wang](https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-wang-16550a5).

The internship has been off to a great start. I have been going through the docs and understanding the hpcc platform in general. The platform is quite complex, with a lot of moving parts interacting amongst themselves, so I need to understand this before I really begin working. I will be writing more on this in the coming weeks.

But for today, the internship is really coming on well. HPCC is an excellent employer and most importantly I would like to give a shout out to Xiaoming and Kevin for being wonderful mentors. I although am new here and don't know much but these guys have been at the forefront to help me out whenever I need. So yes, thanks a lot Ming and Kevin. Looking forward to working with you.

That's it for today. Thanks for reading this.
Yash</content><author><name>Yash Jain</name></author><category term="internship" /><category term="hpcc" /><summary type="html">Hi there. I just finished the first week of my internship at HPCC systems. Those who don’t know about the company, here’s a breif intro from the their about page The HPCC Systems platform is a set of easy-to-use software features, enabling developers and data scientists to process and analyze data at any scale. I am working on making the deployment easier. I will be using Juju cluster deployment framework to achieve this. I am being mentored by Xiaoming Wang and Kevin Wang. The internship has been off to a great start. I have been going through the docs and understanding the hpcc platform in general. The platform is quite complex, with a lot of moving parts interacting amongst themselves, so I need to understand this before I really begin working. I will be writing more on this in the coming weeks. But for today, the internship is really coming on well. HPCC is an excellent employer and most importantly I would like to give a shout out to Xiaoming and Kevin for being wonderful mentors. I although am new here and don’t know much but these guys have been at the forefront to help me out whenever I need. So yes, thanks a lot Ming and Kevin. Looking forward to working with you. That’s it for today. Thanks for reading this. Yash</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Blog!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/20/hello-hydeout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Blog!!" /><published>2017-02-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/20/hello-hydeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/20/hello-hydeout.html">Finally my first blog post!! Thanks to Andrew Fong for this awesone hydeout theme.</content><author><name>Yash Jain</name></author><summary type="html">Finally my first blog post!! Thanks to Andrew Fong for this awesone hydeout theme.</summary></entry></feed>